<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

Luiz Pereira

luizfelipesantospereira01@gmail.com

Frontend developer with over 3 years of professional experience and a strong background in React.js. My focus lies in crafting user interfaces and enhancing user experiences. Actively seeking a role as a Web developer to further leverage my skills and contribute to challenging projects in the field.

Experience

Frontend Developer

Nova Tendência (New Tendency)

May 2023 - Current

- Contributed to the development of web apps with high traffic and significant volumes of data using React.js, Redux for state management, and Material UI for user interface components.
- Participated in the implementation of strategies to ensure the scalability of the application, meeting the growing demands of users. Utilized Jest for comprehensive testing to maintain code quality and reliability.
- Worked on large-scale projects and solved challenges associated with high application usage.

Frontend Developer

Softeam

September 2021 - May 2023

- Developed and maintained several web apps using React, Tailwind CSS for efficient styling, and Node.js, resulting in better user experience and greater efficiency for customers.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designers and product managers, to conceptualize and release new features. Utilized Figma for design collaboration and prototyping.
- Contributed to the implementation of TypeScript to enhance code quality and maintainability, resulting in more robust and scalable applications.

Education

Computer Science

Estácio de Sá University

August 2020 - December 2024

- Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science. GPA: 4.0;
- Curriculum: Analytic Geometry and Linear Algebra; Systems Modeling; Quality and Software Testing; Cloud Computing; Architecture of Distributed Systems; Artificial Intelligence...

Analysis and Systems Development

Estácio de Sá University

July 2020 - December 2022

- Associate of Science degree in Analysis and Systems Development. GPA: 3.7;
- Curriculum: Operating Systems; Databases; Algorithms; Programming languages; Comp. Architecture; Entrepreneurial Engineering; Data Structures; Calculus III.

Projects

Sharenow (2023). Image-based social media app. | React, Tailwind CSS, Sanity.

Cream Ice (2023). A vanilla responsive javascript website for an ice cream parlor. | HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Ignews (2022). A newsletter on react-related topics with a subscription method and social media login. | React, Next.js, Sass, Stripe.

Languages

English: Advanced. Portuguese: Native. Spanish: Basic

Technologies and Tools

- React.js, Javascript, Redux, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS.
- Visual Studio Code, Slack, Postgresgl, Vercel, Git.